RG 062:129, Town of Somers
Connecticut State Library
Town of Somers records
1758-1937
Connecticut State Library
Somers (Conn.)
22.5 cubic feet
Administrative, military, land, vital, school and tax records for the town of Somers.
RG062_129
T000994
Historical Note
The town of Somers was named in July 1734 and annexed to Connecticut in May 1749.
Scope and Content
Administrative, military, land, vital, school and tax records for the town of Somers.
Index Terms
Alternate Creators:
Connecticut. Justice of the Peace (Somers)
Subjects:
Soldiers -- Connecticut -- Somers; Deeds -- Connecticut -- Somers; School enrollment -- Connecticut -- Somers -- Statistics; Schools -- Connecticut -- Somers -- History -- Sources; Justices of the peace -- Connecticut -- Somers; Writs -- Connecticut -- Somers; Voting registers -- Connecticut -- Somers; Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- Somers -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- Somers -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- Somers -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- Somers -- Registers
Places:
Somers (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Somers (Conn.) -- Statistics, Vital
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1758-1937
  - Selectmen's reports, 1830-1879 (Box Box 1)
  - Constable's bonds, 1879-1902 (Box Box 1)
  - Highway surveys and layouts, 1761-1876 (Box Box 1)
  - Military service records, 1800-1914 (Box Box 1)
  - World War I service records and honor roll, 1917-1919 (Box Box 1)
  - Liquor licenses, 1824-1839 (Box Box 1)
  - Deeds and leases received for registration, 1758-1933 (Box Box 2)
  - Abstracts of births, marriages and deaths, 1852-1897 (Box Box 2)
  - First School Society records, including Board of Visitors records and treasurer's accounts, 1796-1897 (Box Box 3)
  - Ninth School district records, 1841-1898 (Box Box 3)
  - Enumeration of school children reports, 1859-1936 (Box Box 4)
  - Board of Education correspondence, 1924-1936 (Box Box 5)
  - Somers Creamery Co. record book, annual report and incorporation papers, 1888 (Box Box 5)
  - Somersville Co. Constitution, annual reports and record book, 1839-1852 (Box Box 5)
  - Assorted records, undated (Box Box 5)
  - Town Treasurers' account books, 1758-1914 (Box Boxes 6-7)
  - Town Deposit Fund accounts, 1837-1908 (Box Box 8)
  - Justice of the peace records, writs, attachments [Primarily gift from H.A. Hamilton and Loren Griswold], 1807-1905 (Box Boxes 9-12)
  - Tax lists, 1797-1820 (Box Box 13)
  - Grand lists, 1801-1863 (Box Box 13)
  - Individual tax lists, 1826 (Box Box 13)
  - Abatements, 1813-1866 (Box Box 13)
  - Assessors' books, 1861-1927 (Box Boxes 14-15)
    scattered
  - Personal tax collectors' books, 1925-1931 (Box Box 16)
  - School district assessment lists, 1841-1888 (Box Box 16)
  - Tax abstracts
    Tax abstracts for 1914-1933 are not boxed.
    - 1819-1843 (Box Box 17)
    - 1844-1850, 1876 (Box Box 18)
    - 1851, 1852, 1853, 1855, 1856, 1857, 1858, 1859 (Box Box 19)
    - 1861, 1862, 1863, 1864, 1865, 1866, 1867, 1868, 1869 (Box Box 20)
    - 1870, 1871, 1872, 1873, 1874, 1875, 1876, 1877, 1878, 1879 (Box Box 21)
    - 1880, 1881, 1882, 1883, 1884, 1885, 1886, 1887, 1888, 1889 (Box Box 22)
    - 1890, 1891, 1892, 1893, 1894 (Box Box 23)
    - 1895, 1896, 1897, 1898, 1899 (Box Box 24)
    - 1900, 1901, 1902, 1903, 1904, 1905 (Box Box 25)
    - 1906, 1907, 1908, 1909, 1910, 1911, 1912, 1913 (Box Box 26)
    - 1914, 1 volume
    - 1915, 1 volume
    - 1916, 1 volume
    - 1917, 1 volume
    - 1918, 1 volume
    - 1919, 1 volume
    - 1920, 1 volume
    - 1921, 1 volume
    - 1922, 1 volume
    - 1923, 1 volume
    - 1924, 1 volume
    - 1925, 1 volume
    - 1926, 1 volume
    - 1927, 1 volume
    - 1928, 1 volume
    - 1929, 1 volume
    - 1930, 1 volume
    - 1931, 1 volume
    - 1932, 1 volume
    - 1933, 1 volume
  - Somersville Co. records, 1839-1852 (Box Box 27)
  - Town accounts, 1758-1842 (Box Box 27)
  - Town accounts, 1828-1842 (Box Box 27)
  - Selectman's book, 1790-1822 (Box Box 27)
  - Lists of Electors, 1866-1883 (Box Box 27)
  - Lists of Electors, 1840-1937; 1 bundle (Box Oversize)